<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on acode.ninja</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on acode.ninja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Lawrence Goldstien</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>recursive file upload to s3 in terraform</title><link>/posts/2019-09-10-recursive-s3-upload-in-terraform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2019-09-10-recursive-s3-upload-in-terraform/</guid><description>
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a lot with HashiCorp&amp;rsquo;s terraform recently. From learning how to set up a highly available container based infrastructure using AWS ECS, to setting up a CloudFront distribution for a static site hosted on S3.
One problem I have had to solve a number of times, is uploading the contents of a directory recursively to an S3 bucket. With the help of a post from Andy Dote&amp;rsquo;s blog, I was able to get some files uploaded.</description></item><item><title>limit http requests with nginx</title><link>/posts/2019-04-21-limit-api-requests-with-nginx/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2019-04-21-limit-api-requests-with-nginx/</guid><description>
There are several ways that you can throttle the rate at which requests to your web application are processed.
Rate limiting within your authentication mechanism is undoubtedly useful. However, the chances are that this requires several calls to database and cache. Database queries could become a costly operation when your application is running under load.
To provide an extra layer of filtering, Nginx is capable of limiting request rates using the ngx_http_limit_req_module module.</description></item><item><title>laravel testing: database reset with seeding</title><link>/posts/2018-10-30-laravel-testing-database-refresh-with-seeding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018-10-30-laravel-testing-database-refresh-with-seeding/</guid><description>
Testing a Laravel application has a low barrier to entry compared to other PHP frameworks. What happens when you want to nuke the database between tests? I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a solution here.
feature testing One of the great features Laravel provides is the ability to refresh your database after each test. This has been really useful, but I needed to test verbs like DELETE and a simple php artisan migrate:fresh isn&amp;rsquo;t all that useful when you have seeds that add information to your database that your tests rely on.</description></item><item><title>warning users about insecure passwords</title><link>/posts/2018-03-19-warning-users-about-insecure-passwords/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018-03-19-warning-users-about-insecure-passwords/</guid><description>
laravel pwned passwords validator This small guide expects you to have my pwned passwords validator for laravel 5.6. It&amp;rsquo;s painless to install and set up:
$ composer require acodeninja/laravel-pwned-passwords-validator Once installed, Laravel&amp;rsquo;s package discovery will take care of loading the package for use in your application. Read more about using the validator.
checking passwords and warning users on login To check if a password is secure each time a user logs in you can use the validator.</description></item><item><title>laravel pwned passwords validator</title><link>/posts/2018-03-15-laravel-pwned-passwords-validator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018-03-15-laravel-pwned-passwords-validator/</guid><description>
a bit about pwned passwords So, a while ago the pwned passwords database was made available to the public. It was a great idea, a collection of all the discrete passwords that had been included in all the data breaches from ';&amp;ndash;have i been pwned?. Annoyingly to check this database with version 1 of the api you could only specify a username to see if that was included in a breach.</description></item><item><title>laravel mix - lazy loading Vue components</title><link>/posts/2018-03-13-laravel-mix-lazy-loading-components/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018-03-13-laravel-mix-lazy-loading-components/</guid><description>
why? Lazy loading components gives a great performance improvement. Larger components can take ages to load and result in an unusable page for a few seconds while the massive app.js file is loaded.
how? You can follow these steps on the tutorial repo.
1. babel plugins You will need to add both the babel-plugin-dynamic-import-webpack and babel-plugin-syntax-dynamic-import packages to your package.json
$ npm install --save-dev \ babel-plugin-dynamic-import-webpack \ babel-plugin-syntax-dynamic-import tutorial commit</description></item><item><title>dot files and the search for the perfect bash setup</title><link>/posts/2018-03-12-dot-files-and-the-search-for-the-perfect-bash-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018-03-12-dot-files-and-the-search-for-the-perfect-bash-setup/</guid><description>
Discussion about what makes a good bash prompt. Including examples.</description></item><item><title>i designed a game - pugilica</title><link>/posts/2017-02-20-i-designed-a-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2017-02-20-i-designed-a-game/</guid><description>
Coming up with a great game idea was a lot harder than I initially thought, but then why did I think it would be easy anyway?
Enter Pugilica, a game I thought up while toying with some dice and card mechanics. The basic mechanic for the game would be players taking turns to roll the dice, the roll deciding how many cards they could play that turn to effect other players.</description></item><item><title>a few thoughts on ad-blockers</title><link>/posts/2017-01-04-a-few-thoughts-on-ad-blockers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2017-01-04-a-few-thoughts-on-ad-blockers/</guid><description>
Although content creators should have the opportunity to generate income from their work, this should not be at the expense of the end user.
Online advertising networks have a responsibility to ensure that the content they are delivering does not contain malware. Advertisers need to ensure that their content makes efficient use of system resources.
Adverts should complement the content on a page, rather than being specific to the end user.</description></item><item><title>html5 document ready</title><link>/posts/2016-06-08-html5-document-ready/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-06-08-html5-document-ready/</guid><description>
DOMContentLoaded,
document ready or not?
jQuery: overhead.
document.addEventListener(&amp;#34;DOMContentLoaded&amp;#34;, function(event) { console.log(&amp;#39;document load time: &amp;#39; + event.timeStamp); });</description></item><item><title>object.create, applying prototypes</title><link>/posts/2016-06-07-object-create-applying-prototypes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-06-07-object-create-applying-prototypes/</guid><description>
prototyping chaining,
object extension for all the
modern programmers
var Ninja = function () {}; Ninja.prototype.throw = function (item) { console.log(&amp;#39;Throwing &amp;#39; + item); }; var Shinobi = function () {}; Shinobi.prototype = Object.create(Ninja.prototype); var shinobi = new Shinobi; shinobi.throw(&amp;#39;knife&amp;#39;); // Throwing knife</description></item><item><title>frozen objects</title><link>/posts/2016-06-03-frozen-objects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-06-03-frozen-objects/</guid><description>
objects are frozen,
never to be extended
or altered again
class Ninja { constructor() { this.dead = false; Object.freeze(this); } } var shinobi = new Ninja(); shinobi.dead = true; console.log(shinobi); // Ninja { dead: false }</description></item><item><title>information hiding</title><link>/posts/2016-06-02-information-hiding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-06-02-information-hiding/</guid><description>
object oriented
information hiding done.
closures: private methods
class Person { constructor(name, dob) { var dob = dob; this.name = name; this.getBirthyear = () =&amp;gt; new Date(dob).getFullYear(); } } var person = new Person(&amp;#39;thejsninja&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;1985-12-04&amp;#39;); console.log(person.getBirthyear()); // 1985</description></item><item><title>javascript, still a thing?</title><link>/posts/2016-06-01-javascript-still-a-thing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-06-01-javascript-still-a-thing/</guid><description>
Javascript is a great, and expressive language. You can be as succinct or vague as you like, you can scratch the surface or leverage a really powerful event loop.
alert(&amp;#39;Annoying popup&amp;#39;); Lots of people just think of the annoying browser popup, but you can deeper than that.
Classes can be defined, albeit through some syntax sugar over the top of javascript’s prototype inheritance.
&amp;#39;use strict&amp;#39;; class Person { constructor(firstname, lastname) { this.</description></item><item><title>what i am listening to june 2013</title><link>/posts/2013-06-01-what-i-am-listening-to-june-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013-06-01-what-i-am-listening-to-june-2013/</guid><description>
I think these posts might turn into a series! I was searching through soundcloud the other day and came across TheBluesMobile.com a blues show on soundcloud. The interview and bio/history of Hot Tuna brought me in, but then on came The California Honeydrops a blues / gospel / new orleans jazz band. I am now hooked and as soon as pay day comes around will be buying their new album Like you mean it.</description></item><item><title>get a stream of tweets</title><link>/posts/2013-05-21-get-a-stream-of-tweets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013-05-21-get-a-stream-of-tweets/</guid><description>
The first part of the course I have been taking on data science deals with analysis of Twitter data. This is aimed at discerning the overall sentiment of a Tweet or collection of tweets.
To get this going the first thing you need is a big collection of tweets in a format that is easy for a program to digest. Step in JSON, a text based output that represents data in a collection of arrays.</description></item><item><title>what i am listening to: may 2013</title><link>/posts/2013-05-19-what-i-am-listening-to-may-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013-05-19-what-i-am-listening-to-may-2013/</guid><description>
It has been a while since I last put anything up here so I thought just sticking up a post with my latest listening experience might be the way to go. A while ago Wil Wheaton stuck a Zoe Keating track on This is my Jam called Tetrishead, fell in love with it while walking around the downs in Bristol (UK).
So today while at my day job I am listening to Zoe Keating’s Album “Into the Trees”.</description></item><item><title>centre without text align center</title><link>/posts/2013-02-27-centre-without-text-align-center/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013-02-27-centre-without-text-align-center/</guid><description>
CSS is great for changing things around on a page but knowing the best way to accomplish something when you are just starting out is difficult. So how do you centre block level elements, and what on earth are block level elements anyway? Well for a list of html elements that are block level check out the MDN site here: https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/HTML/Block-level_elements
So now we know what they are what is the best way to centre them on a page or within a parent element?</description></item><item><title>testing login to an smtp server using telnet</title><link>/posts/2013-02-26-testing-login-to-an-smtp-server-using-telnet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013-02-26-testing-login-to-an-smtp-server-using-telnet/</guid><description>
So if you are having problems sending emails there is always one sure fire way to establish if the problem is your connection or not. This can be done using the telnet application, a command line tool that is included in most operating systems.
To do this you will need to open the command prompt, on windows you can do this by pressing the windows key and tapping the R button once.</description></item><item><title>the c in css</title><link>/posts/2013-02-26-the-c-in-css/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013-02-26-the-c-in-css/</guid><description>
CSS is a very powerful tool for web designers and developers, as with all great tools you need to know how to use it effectively to get things right. This article covers some fundamentals about the Cascading part of CSS to give you a better handle on how your CSS affects the HTML content of sites you work on.
Cascade based on style location So, what does it mean by Cascade?</description></item><item><title>nginx ssl only configuration</title><link>/posts/2013-01-08-nginx-ssl-only-configuration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013-01-08-nginx-ssl-only-configuration/</guid><description>
Configuring Nginx with SSL can be a bit of a nightmare to do properly. Here is a handy config file I use as a starting base for it.
#HTTP Redirect server { # Set up the port listener listen 80; listen [IPV6]:80 default ipv6only=on; # Set the hostname to be served server_name SITE www.SITE; # Set up access and error logs accesslog /var/www/SITE/logs/nginx.access.log; errorlog /var/www/SITE/logs/nginx.error.log; # Redirect all requests on http to https location / { rewrite ^ https://$servername$requesturi?</description></item><item><title>msd fail</title><link>/posts/2012-10-19-msd-fail/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2012-10-19-msd-fail/</guid><description>
When security fails it’s all good to point and laugh but sometimes it really isn’t funny.
The MSD (Ministry of Social Development) in New Zealand set up a kiosk system to assist with job seeking at local centres around the country. Unfortunately they didn&amp;rsquo;t heed the security report produced by Dimension Data and left open a gaping hole into their enterprise network.
This hole was accessible by one of the oldest tricks in the book, Microsoft Word’s File &amp;gt; Open &amp;gt; Browse Network.</description></item><item><title>nginx install on debian</title><link>/posts/2012-09-26-nginx-install-on-debian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2012-09-26-nginx-install-on-debian/</guid><description>
It took ages to try, and find a guide that actually helps with installing Nginx on a Debian system. Most either involve compiling from source or are incomplete to the point of leaving you with a useless system.
So there are a number of steps to take to get Nginx up and running on a Debian system, and I will cover my way here.
Step 1 – sources.list First step is to get the sources for Nginx and php5-fpm into your apt source list.</description></item><item><title>nginx config files</title><link>/posts/2012-09-12-nginx-config-files/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2012-09-12-nginx-config-files/</guid><description>
Ever since moving to Nginx I have had the self satisfied smile of someone who knows his web applications are going to be snappy. That&amp;rsquo;s not just down to good coding, but down to the quality of the server software employed.
One problem that I came across with Nginx was implementing features found in the .htaccess files you would usually use to set per site and directory settings within PHP and Apache.</description></item></channel></rss>